let's start off by talking about
belongings in your daily life do you
prefer having fewer or more belongings
in your daily life I think personally
for me I'd prefer having fewer
belongings just because I feel like it
would be more easier to deal with on a
daily basis especially when it comes
with technology trying to decide like if
I had a laptop and an iPad and a phone I
have all three of like the same kind of
thing I just think it would be easier to
find function in life with less what
things can you not live without ooh um
my phone I can't I can't live without my
phone um what else can't I live without
water always staying
hydrated um and my
cats how do you organize your
belongings sometimes I do it by color if
it was like things related to books I
like to organize them by colors on the
shelves yeah now let's talk about
technology in Modern Life how has
technology changed your life I think
technology has changed my life in so
many different ways one of them being um
the ability to to connect with people um
I have personally I have a lot of
long-distance friends and uh technology
has allowed me to stay in touch with
those people and even though they don't
they're not with you personally you do
feel like you never miss that connection
because of technology and I think work
related technology offers um me a lot of
opportunity to connect and network with
many different kind of people would you
like to have more technology in your
life or less technology in your life I
personally would like to have less
technology in my life just because I
feel like technology sometimes
defeats the purpose of humanity in a
sense of if there's too much of it like
like nowadays with the AI and all of
that it's kind of starting to replace
human beings in in a sense and um yeah I
would like to depend Less on technology
generally do you think technology has
made your life better now than in the
past when you had less technology yes to
a certain an extent just because I feel
like back then we didn't have Instagram
we didn't have those social media um the
iconic social media platforms that all
young teenagers use and those are the
main platforms people are using now to
connect with people and to network and
especially if you're running your own
business for example like trying to
share your music or share art that's how
you um come out to a bigger platform so
definitely I feel like it has a bigger
Advantage than what we had in the past
now let's talk about reading do you
enjoy reading I do enjoy reading but I
wish I did more of it I feel like with
um technology and all the modern um
things coming up I feel like I used to
read more as a child and I'm trying to
get back into it some of the things I
love reading about are self-help books
those are my favorite now let's talk
about outdoor activities what activities
do you like to do outdoors outdoors I
love to go running sometimes I like to
do morning yogas I've had yogas by the
beach
before um I really love joining group
classes Outdoors as well I once did this
thing um where we started off with a
morning yoga and then it went into a hit
workout and then a yoga cool down I love
to go swimming I love the ocean I love
to be by the
beach um and yeah how often do you spend
time outside um not as often as I would
like just because given the location I'm
in right now it gets pretty hot and
humid and I wish our weather was would
accommodate um being outdoors more often
but I try my best to be outside as much
as possible when you're outside do you
prefer being alone or or with other
people I think I prefer being alone just
because it gives you that space to be
with yourself and to disconnect from
everyone around you for me personally
sometimes I feel like when I'm around
people my social battery dies very
quickly and it could be um it could be a
lot to take in both have their
advantages and disadvantages of course
I'd love to hang out with my friends and
be around my friends but I recently did
a solo trip to England and I spent most
of my time by myself in nature walking
around the city and I find that one
learns a lot when they spend time with
their s and um the energies around them
in the future would you like to do more
activities outdoors yes for sure um I
always wanted to try out
paragliding skiing skiing has been one
of like an outdoor activity I'd always
wanted to do a t time where I had to
adapt to a new situation it came when I
graduated from high school and I had to
finally move to college and I was one of
the people that decided ultimately to
move out of my home place to go abroad
for a university just because I felt
like University had University abroad
had more resources and opportunity it
was pretty difficult to fit in um people
have different culture over there
different um outlook on life but I
needed to adapt
because that was the only way I could
grow in that environment I think that
some days where better than
others um it was pretty difficult in the
beginning just because I felt like um in
the beginning you feel very out of place
like for example when I started my
degree I didn't really had prior
experience to um the art world and
everything related to the art World from
in my home country so when I moved I
kind of was like that one student um in
between everyone that was um
inexperienced or less experienced and it
got to me sometimes sometimes I I cried
in class I had my breakdowns but I think
I learned a lot that you keep pushing
through in those situations it could be
so easy to cave in to the bad or the
negative but if you just take it as a
learning experience and keep moving
after a year two years pass by one
starts to acclimate to their environment
and one starts to adapt properly we have
been talking about a new situation you
had to adapt to we're going to continue
to talk about change and adaptation and
personal growth things like that why do
some people find it harder to adapt to
change than others
to thank you for watching this video I
want to give you a free course that has
helped thousands of students improve
their I speaking score what it's going
to do is take you through every single
part of the test and give you strategies
for part one part two and part three and
also allow you to practice at home for
free and get feedback to sign up for
that for free all you have to do is just
click the link in the description thanks
very much and let's get back to the
video I think as human beings we we
don't like change I think humans like to
stay the same we grow up our brain our
brain the way it's formulated um is that
we get specific programs put into us
when we're kids and straying away from
those kind of programs whether it's the
environment you grew up in or the
relationships you've had throughout your
life I think it it puts the the human
being in a state of fight or flight
that's why some people resist changed or
or never want to change now let's talk
about cultural adaptation why do some
people adapt more easily to living
abroad than others I think sometimes a
person finds themselves abroad um maybe
that culture fits them more as a person
as a soul um I think that sometimes
people find they they empathize with the
people that they they live with outside
and if one is reserved in in their home
country and decides to move out they
they open themselves up to different
experiences and I think when one finds
that freedom and that belonging
somewhere else they they start to adapt
a new lifestyle and way of living what
challenges do people face when adopting
to a new culture one of the many
challenges I think people people face
when adapting to a new culture
is sometimes there are some things about
that culture that will not resonate with
you as a person for example me
personally I decided to ultimately move
out of America after I got my degree
just because there were a couple of
values in that culture that personally I
didn't resonate with and um I found it
better to find elsewhere somewhere
elsewhere where um
I could feel more at home and more like
everything was in coherence with me and
last question in part three how does
facing challenges help people develop as
individuals I think facing
challenges most importantly makes you
listen to yourself more makes you follow
your gut more um and I'm a personal
believer that nobody grows without pain
pain and going through challenges I
think pain is a big um life teacher it's
um something that people have to go
through in order to become a better
version of themselves well done I'm
going to give you some feedback now my
feedback will be on part one and then
part two part three so we're going to
talk more strategic tactical things that
you could do to ensure you get the
highest score possible and that people
watching at home can learn from that and
then we're also to talk about your band
score so pronunciation fluency grammar
vocabulary what would I give you how
would I help you get the highest score
possible so part one to thank you for
making it this far in the video I want
to give you 10% off our VIP course I VIP
course is the most successful ILS course
in the world that is a fact because we
have more band seven eight and nine
success stories than any other I course
in the entire world we do that by
simplifying the whole I process
supporting you with some of the best is
teachers in the world and being with you
every step of the way until you get the
score that you need all you have to do
is just look down in the description
just click that and you can sign up if
you have any questions about the VIP
course always feel free to get in touch
with us we answer 100% of the questions
that we get hope that you become a VIP
if not enjoy the rest of this free video
part one you did something that many
many people do which is you were quite
nervous in the beginning and that
affected your fluency a little bit
myself as a native English speaker if I
was doing this test the first few
answers probably wouldn't be the most
fluent ones because you are a little
nervous in the beginning that is why in
part one they don't start off with the
really difficult questions they just
throw little uh little getting to know
your questions at you but you cope
pretty well after that so as you as you
went on your answers became more fluent
and you became less nervous and a good
examiner will recognize that a lot of
people think that if you have one bad
answer that you immediately get a low
score that's not how the test works the
examiner will base your your score on
the totality of your answers for example
you gave some very short answers at the
beginning or you just were like oh
listed lots of different things The
Examiner knows that's just nerves based
on your subsequent answers so pick the
things that are easy to talk about and
it's okay to have some nerves just
understand that that's part of the test
part two similar thing at the beginning
of part two you could tell that you were
thinking a lot you were trying to come
up with the best ideas I think is that
true or or not so remember that it's not
an ideas test it is a speaking test a
lot of people think that they'll get a
higher score or sound more impressive if
they choose the best ideas the best
ideas are the ones that are easiest for
you to talk about the simplest ideas at
the beginning your fluency wasn't bad or
anything like that but it was just that
you were you could tell that the the
cogs in your brain were were working
over time trying to think of the correct
thing and our brains are obviously
connected to our speech and if our
brains are overworked just like a
computer with too many tabs open then
the speech coming out will be affected
sometimes it wasn't that affected but
again the examiner won't listen to the
first few sentences and go terrible
fluency let's not that it was Terri but
a lot of people watching think that
that's the case they've been taught in
their school that if you know they don't
sound fluent the entire time that
they're going to get a lower score that
is not the case but overall your part
two was great some great vocabulary some
great grammar but on test day you might
get a question that you don't feel
comfortable talking about or is just
unusual for you that could affect your
fluency because unusual topic plus
overthinking could lead to you just
having fluency issues so again my advice
is pretty repetitive but you know talk
about the things that are easy to talk
about know that it's not a performance
it's a conversation all right so
sometimes it felt like you were
performing rather than talking to me
everybody's different some people don't
like making eye contact but when you
were thinking you were looking away and
looking up like a lot of students do
that they always look up maybe that's
part of your brain that deals with ideas
and you can tell they're really thinking
deeply when you did that you were
thinking a lot and that your fluency
suffered at times you did this thing as
well you did it at the start of part two
and you did it in in part three where
you think and speak at the same time and
you usually repeat the question so what
you do is you're like so describe a time
when you had to adapt to a new
situation so you're talking on thinking
all at the same time on repeating the
question a better way might be to just
give yourself a little bit more time you
don't have to answer immediately think
about it for a second or two and just
say that's that's an interesting
question I haven't thought about that
one before or that's a that's a really
good question let me think about that
for a second and then give your your
answer because some examiners might
think that you're just repeating the
question back at them so that's not
really showing how great your English is
and your fluency is not great at the
same time the first 10 20% of your
answers the fluency seems to be lower
than the final 80 90% because you're
thinking what to say yes does that make
sense yes yes yeah is that helpful you
probably don't need even know you're
doing it it's probably just a habit um
and in normal life you probably don't
need to do that but we want to make sure
that you get one of the top marks
another way that you could improve
especially your part three um would be
to include more examples so you talk
generally about situations that happened
like when you were crying in college or
the values that you disagreed with maybe
you didn't want to say that cuz you
don't want to be controversial or
whatever you want to be you know not
offend anyone but in the real test you
know the cameras are not rolling nobody
feel free to give those real examples
cuz they're often easier to talk about
another way is just to to imagine you're
talking to someone who doesn't know
anything about what you're talking about
and you need to help them understand all
right so using examples is just a way
that human beings help it's just a
Communications tool explanations are
Communications tools again nothing bad
uh but we want to make sure that you get
one of the top marks um and these are
just me being overly cautious and
helping the people learn at home as well
so what scores would you get the best
part of your performance is your
pronunciation even though you didn't
grow up in an English speaking country
you have picked up the accent you don't
sign like an American per se but you
don't sign like you're from Lebanon or
either now you don't get extra marks for
siging American but you do get extra
marks for being as clear as possible and
the thing about the American accent not
a lot of people know this but the reason
why the American accent is generally
clear is because so many people from so
many different parts of the world mve to
America so everybody developed this
accent that is super clear so it's
actually a good accent to to have forun
standard
you know most people in the world will
be able to understand you Me I'm Irish
not everyone
understands the Irish accent so I'm not
saying that anybody watching needs to
you know move to America or learn the
the American accent but having that
accent for you it doesn't sound forced
it doesn't sound like you're putting it
on it sounds like that's your natural
accent and it really does help
communication the other thing that
spending time in America has helped you
do is to sound more like a native
English speaker with things like
intonation connected speech word stress
this is where we show meaning through
for example our voices going up or
voices going down like for example when
we're listing things I like sushi and I
like Italian food and I like steak and I
also like Indian food so I went up and I
went up and I went up and then I went
down at the end that's I'm listing I'm
listing I'm listing now I'm done so I'm
conveying meaning through tone yes not
through actual words and you do that
very very well so band nine for
pronunciation very very good you also
have amazing vocabulary things that many
English speakers would not be able to
use one I noted Dar was draining a
social battery I really like that was
that was quite poetic the reason why
that is so good is that you used fewer
words to explain means something quite
complicated draining of a social battery
what does what does that actually mean
it means that you are maybe an
introverted person that when you're
around other people you have less energy
you like to be alone and that boosts
your energy a little bit that took me
what three or four sentences to explain
that or I can just say something like it
drains my social battery so it is very
precise and very economical and elegant
and you had lots of examples of that
like this for vocabulary you would
definitely get a b nine grammar you do
make some little tiny slips like this
that is totally normal even for native
English speakers a lot of people think
that if you make one tiny little
grammatical error you're going to get a
bond five or Bond six or something like
that that is not true because even as an
educated native English speaker who
teaches English for a living I make
little grammatical errors every English
speaker does even English teachers make
little grammatical errors and in the
marking criteria it actually says for
band n makes slips very infrequently
that's exactly you you do make tiny
little errors but very infrequently so
you would get a band nine for uh for
grammar okay now your weakest area is
your fluency this is related to the
things that we talked about at the
beginning which is being nervous at the
start so there were a lot of as um like
kind of uh what we call them Audible
pauses like um or fillers like like you
know kind of again even high level
English native English speakers use
those little words when we're nervous um
I'm doing it right now and so don't
worry too much about it but for the
purposes of an is test the less nervous
that you are um the better your fluency
is going to be also you have that issue
of when you're thinking it slows down
the pace that you're speaking at and you
also have more of those audible pauses
nerves can be solved quite easily
through preparation so doing stuff like
this with me and me giving you feedback
you're going to be a lot less nervous
going into the real test because youve
like I've been there done that I've I've
practice so much so it's going to be a
walk in the park for you and the other
thing is try less to perform and more
conversation I know it's difficult not
every examiner is someone that you would
consider a friend but you know for 15
minutes pretend you're talking to a
friend in a coffee shop literally
picture that friend or that family
member and they're asking you these
questions and I think that will really
really help your fluency coherence is
fine you're answering every question
you're developing them enough I think
examples could also help with that just
pick really really simple things there's
nothing in the marketing criteria that
talks about levels of ideas you don't
get extra marks for good ideas you get
extra marks for pronunciation fluency
grammar vocabulary so everything that
you do all the advice that I'm giving
you is designed to help those things and
for someone like you at a very very high
level it is more important that we
simplify your ideas cuz you're not
thinking about English so much you're
thinking about how do I give the the
best answer the best idea and that can
actually hinder your fluence M so that
would be but overall I think you would
get a about nine but on a bad day you
know let's say you didn't sleep the
night before and you didn't get a good
breakfast and you're late and then you
get a question that's that you're not
happy with and you try to overperform
that could drop you down and but we I
don't think it's going to happen but
well done thank you